Xi Peng

4400 Vestal Parkway East Vestal, NY 13850, USA +1 (917) 803-7402 • xpeng@binghamton.edu https://sites.google.com/site/xipengcshomepage/

RESEARCH INTEREST

Deep Learning, Machine Learning, and Intelligent Data Analytics such as Vision/Language Understanding. Training deep models usually requires intensive human efforts such as tons of data annotations and specialized training skills. My research aims to answer the question: can we reduce the efforts to achieve more efficient machine intelligence? More specifically,

- Can we reduce the data efforts by learning data augmentation?
 - Learning to learn in multimodality understanding: [ECCV'18] [AAAI'18 review]
 - Competitive and competitive data augmentation: [CVPR'18] [TPAMI'18 review]
 - Adversarial image and video generation: [IJCAI'18] [ECCV'18]
- Can we improve the network performance by leveraging domain knowledge?
 - Learning disentangled representations: [ECCV'16 oral] [ICCV'17] [IJCV'17]
 - Learning factorization and forecasting: [IJCV'18] [TVCG'18 review] [BMVC'18]
 - Attribute editing and retargeting: [CVIU'15] [BMVC'16] [ECCV'18]
- My research has been successfully applied in human-centered AI analytics funded by NSF/NASA:
 - Vision-based workspace injury prevention and rehabilitation: [FG'18] [JOB'18] [THMS'18 review]
 - Detecting Early Stages of Cognitive Fatigue: [ACCV'10 oral] [TIP'12] [CVPRW'16]
 - Computational American sign language analysis: [ICCV'15] [ICPR'16 oral] [FG'16]

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, New Jersey, USA

■ Ph.D. in Computer Science

- Sep 2012 Oct 2017
- Thesis: Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Visual Understanding
- Adviser: Prof. Dimitris N Metaxas

Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Science, Beijing, China

■ M.S. in Computer Science

- Sep 2008 Jul 2011
- Thesis: Multi-scale Visual Object Tracking (Outstanding Master Dissertation)
- Adviser: Prof. Ming Tang

Beihang University, Beijing, China

■ B.S. in Automation Science

Sep 2004 – Jul 2008

EXPERIENCE

Binghamton University - State University of New York, Binghamton, New York, USA

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science

Sep 2018 – Now

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, New Jersey, USA

Visiting Professor, Department of Computer Science

Oct 2018 – Oct 2020

NEC Labs America, Cupertino, California, USA

Research Intern, Media Analytics Group

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

IBM T. J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown Heights, New York, USA

• Research Intern, Vision Group

Jun 2015 – Dec 2015

Baidu Research, Beijing, China

Software Engineer, NLP Group

Jul 2011 - Jun 2012

PUBLICATIONS

JOURNALS

[1]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, Shaoting Zhang, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. A computer vision based method for 3d posture estimation of symmetrical lifting. *Journal of Biomechanics* (**JOB**, *IF*:2.43), 69:40–46, 2018.

- [2]Xi Peng, Rogerio S Feris, Xiaoyu Wang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Red-net: A recurrent encoder-decoder network for video-based face alignment. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (IJCV, IF:11.54), 126(10):1103–1119, 2018.
- [3]**Xi Peng**, Shaoting Zhang, Yang Yu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Toward personalized modeling: Incremental and ensemble alignment for sequential faces in the wild. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (IJCV, *IF*:11.54), 126(2-4):184–197, 2018.
- [4]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, Ahmed Elgammal, and Dimitris Metaxas. From circle to 3-sphere: Head pose estimation by instance parameterization. *Computer Vision and Image Understanding* (CVIU, *IF*:2.39), 136:92–102, 2015.
- [5]Ming Tang and **Xi Peng**. Robust tracking with discriminative ranking lists. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP, IF:5.07)*, 21(7):3273–3281, 2012.

CONFERENCES

- [6]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Shijie Geng, Lingfei Wu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Quantized densely connected u-nets for efficient landmark localization. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (ECCV), 2018.
- [7]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning to forecast and refine residual motion for image-to-video generation. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV**), 2018.
- [8]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning residual motion in video generation. In *Workshops of European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV Workshops**), 2018.
- [9]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Shijie Geng, Yizhe Zhu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Cu-net: Coupled u-nets. In *British Machine Vision Conference* (**BMVC** *Oral*), 2018.
- [10]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Cr-gan: Learning complete representations for multi-view generation. In *International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (IJCAI), 2018.
- [11]**Xi Peng***, Zhiqiang Tang*, Fei Yang, Rogerio S Feris, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Jointly optimize data and network training: Adversarial data augmentation in human pose estimation. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (**CVPR**). * contribute equally, 2018.
- [12]Yizhe Zhu, Mohamed Elhoseiny, Bingchen Liu, **Xi Peng**, and Ahmed Elgammal. A generative adversarial approach for zero-shot learning from noisy texts. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (**CVPR**), 2018.
- [13] Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Zhiqiang Tang, Xu Xu, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. Toward marker-free 3d pose estimation in lifting: A deep multi-view solution. In *IEEE International Conference and Workshops on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition* (**FG**), 2018.
- [14]**Xi Peng**, Xiang Yu, Kihyuk Sohn, Dimitris N Metaxas, and Manmohan Chandraker. Reconstruction-based disentanglement for pose-invariant face recognition. In *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2017.
- [15]**Xi Peng**, Rogerio S Feris, Xiaoyu Wang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. A recurrent encoder-decoder network for sequential face alignment. In *European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV** *Oral*, *Best Student Paper Runner-up*), 2016.
- [16]**Xi Peng**, Qiong Hu, Junzhou Huang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Track facial points in unconstrained videos. *British Machine Vision Conference* (**BMVC**), 2016.
- [17]Xi Peng, Nalini Ratha, and Sharathchandra Pankanti. Learning face recognition from limited training data using deep neural networks. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (ICPR Oral, Best Student Paper Runner-up), 2016.
- [18]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Sequential face alignment via person-specific modeling in the wild. In *Workshops of Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR Workshops), 2016.
- [19]**Xi Peng**, Shaoting Zhang, Yu Yang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Piefa: Personalized incremental and ensemble face alignment. In *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV*), 2015.

- [20]**Xi Peng**, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Three-dimensional head pose estimation in-the-wild. In *IEEE International Conference and Workshops on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition* (**FG**), 2015.
- [21]Xi Peng, Junzhou Huang, Qiong Hu, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Head pose estimation by instance parameterization. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (ICPR), 2014.
- [22]Carol Neidle, Jingjing Liu, Bo Liu, **Xi Peng**, Christian Vogler, and Dimitris Metaxas. Computer-based tracking, analysis, and visualization of linguistically significant nonmanual events in american sign language (asl). In *Workshop of Language Resources and Evaluation Conference* (**LREC Workshops**), 2014.
- [23]Qiong Hu, **Xi Peng**, Peng Yang, Fei Yang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Robust multi-pose facial expression recognition. In *International Conference on Pattern Recognition* (**ICPR**), 2014.
- [24]Ming Tang, **Xi Peng**, and Duowen Chen. Robust tracking with discriminative ranking lists. In *Asian Conference on Computer Vision* (**ACCV** *Oral*), 2010.

MANUSCRIPTS UNDER REVIEW

- [25]Xi Peng, Zhiqiang Tang, Yizhe Zhu, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Coconet: Learning a competitive and cooperative agent for network enhancement. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI under review)*, 2018.
- [26]Zhiqiang Tang, **Xi Peng**, Kang Li, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Towards efficient u-nets: A coupled and quantized approach. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI under review)*, 2018.
- [27]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning dual-agent for improved inference and generation. In *The Thirty-Third AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence* (**AAAI** *under review*), 2018.
- [28]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, and Kang Li. A deep neural network-based method for 3d lifting motion estimation. *Journal of Biomechanics* (**JOB** *under review*), 2018.
- [29]Rahil Mehrizi, **Xi Peng**, Xu Xu, Shaoting Zhang, Dimitris Metaxas, and Kang Li. Predicting 3d lower-back joint load in lifting: A deep pose estimation approach. *IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine System* (**THMS** *under review*), 2018.
- [30]Long Zhao, Fangda Han, **Xi Peng**, Xun Zhang, Mubbasir Kapadia, Vladimir Pavlovic, and Dimitris Metaxas. Sketch-based face editing in videos using identity deformation transfer. *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics* (**TVCG** *under review*), 2018.
- [31]Yu Tian, **Xi Peng**, Long Zhao, Shaoting Zhang, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning complete representations for improved adversarial generation and inference. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV in submission)*, 2018.
- [32]Long Zhao, **Xi Peng**, Mubbasir Kapadia, and Dimitris N Metaxas. Learning residual motions in long-term video generation. *International Journal of Computer Vision* (**IJCV** *in submission*), 2018.

PATENTS

- [33]Xiang Yu, Kihyuk Sohn, Manmohan Chandraker, and **Xi Peng**. Siamese reconstruction convolutional neural network for pose-invariant face recognition, 2018. US Patent under process.
- [34]Sharath U Pankanti, **Xi Peng**, and Nalini K Ratha. Visual object recognition, 2017. US Patent App. 15/089,707.
- [35]Ming Tang and **Xi Peng**. A classification-based multi-scale visual object tracking system, 2010. CASIA Software Patent NO. 2010SRBJ6289.

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

■ IJCV special issue on Best Paper of ECCV'16	2017
■ ICCV 2017 Doctoral Consortium	2017
■ ECCV 2016 Best Student Paper Runner-up (6 out of 1000+)	2016
■ ICPR 2016 Best Student Paper Runner-up	2016
 Outstanding Graduate Student Fellowship, Rutgers 	2013 - 2014
 Outstanding Graduate Student Fellowship, Rutgers 	2012 – 2013

	■ The 17th Beihang "Fengru Cup" Competition Runner-up (26 out of 600+)	2007
	 Excellent Academic Performance Scholarship (Top 1%), Beihang University 	2006
	 Outstanding Academic Performance Scholarship (Top 5%), Beihang University 	2005, 2007
INVITED TALKS	 "Reduce Data and Human Efforts toward More Efficient AI", at CUNY Graduate C Jun 2018 	Center, NYC, USA
	 "Learning Data Augmentation and Disentanglement for Efficient AI", at Steven Instit NJ, USA 	ute of Technology, May 2018
	• "Reduce Data Efforts for More Efficient AI", at Binghamton University - SUNY , N	Y, USA Apr 2018
	 "Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Understanding", at MIT-Watson A Feb 2018 	AI Lab, MA, USA
	"Learning Disentangled Representations in Deep Understanding", at IBM Watson NY, USA	Research Center, Jan 2018
	 "Self-supervised Disentanglement Learning via Feature Reconstruction", at IC Consortium, Venice, Italy 	CCV'17 Doctoral Oct 2017
	 "Deep Visual Understanding: Methods and Applications", at Rutgers Thesis I Oct 2017 	Defense, NJ, USA
	 "Learning Face Recognition from Limited Training Data", at ICPR'16 Oral Pres Mexico 	Sentation , Cancun, Dec 2016
	 "A Recurrent Encoder-Decoder Network for Sequential Face Alignment", at Presentation, Amsterdam, Netherlands 	ECCV'16 Oral Oct 2016
	 "Disentangle Subject and Viewpoint by Feature Reconstruction", at NEC Labs A Aug 2016 	merica, CA, USA
	 "Robust Face Verification by Semi-supervised Alignment", IBM Watson Research Aug 2015 	Center, NY, USA,
CO-ADVISED	Rahil Mehrizi, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Kang Li	Jan 2017 – Now
STUDENTS	 Zhiqiang Tang, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Jan 2017 – Now
	 Yu Tian, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Apr 2017 – Now
	 Long Zhao, Ph.D. student, co-advised with Prof. Dimitris N. Metaxas 	Sep 2017 – Now
TEACHING	■ CS436/CS580L Intro to Machine Learning	Fall 2018
SKILLS	■ Coding: Python, C/C++, OpenCV, OpenGL	
	 Deep Learning: Pytorch, Caffe, Theano 	
	 Systems: Linux, GPU Cluster, Hadoop DFS 	
PROFESSIONAL	Guest Journal Editor:	
ACTIVITES	Neurocomputing (IF:3.32) SI on "Deep feature learning in cross-domain problems."	2018
	Journal Reviewer:	
	■ IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI) IF:9.46	2017, 2018
	■ International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV) IF:11.54	2017, 2018
	■ IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP) IF:5.07	2012, 2016, 2017
	■ IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine System (THMS)	2017, 2018
	■ IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT)	2017
	■ IEEE Access	2017, 2018
	 Neurocomputing 	2016, 2017, 2018
	Pattern Recognition	2016, 2018
	Conference Program Committee:	-
	-	

■ Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)	2019
 Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) 	2018
 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 	2018
■ IEEE Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2018, 2019
■ IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2014, 2016, 2017, 2018
■ European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	2016, 2018
■ IEEE Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2015, 2017
■ Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV)	2018
■ IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face Gesture Recognition (FG)	2018